<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Register your business on Cosec Consultants</title><link>http://localhost/register/</link><description>Recent content in Register your business on Cosec Consultants</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost/register/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Partnership</title><link>http://localhost/register/partnership/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/register/partnership/</guid><description>A type of business organization where two or more persons come together to form a business and divide the profits thereof in an agreed ratio. Partnerships are a very good choice of business entity for small enterprises wherein two or more persons decides to contribute to a business and share the profits or losses. It can be registered or unregistered and can be even registered after formation. However, an unregistered firm cannot file a suit in any court against the firm or other partners for the enforcement of any right arising from a contract or right conferred by the Partnership Act.</description></item><item><title>Nidhi Company</title><link>http://localhost/register/nidhicompany/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/register/nidhicompany/</guid><description>A Nidhi company closely resembles a Non-Banking Finance Company; however under a Nidhi Company, deposits may be accepted from the shareholders of the Nidhi Company. A Nidhi company is registered to borrow and lend to its shareholders to promote the habit of saving money among its shareholders and works on the principle of mutual help. These type of companies are registered as a public company and should have “Nidhi Limited” as the last words of its name.</description></item><item><title>One Person Company</title><link>http://localhost/register/onepersoncompany/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/register/onepersoncompany/</guid><description>A One Person Company is a paradigm shift in the Indian corporate regime, bringing it at par with global standards. Any Natural person who is an Indian citizen and resident in India shall be eligible to incorporate an OPC. It combines the features of sole proprietorship and a company. However, at the time of incorporation, an OPC must nominate a nominee director who will become the owner of the OPC in case the sole director is disabled.</description></item><item><title>Private Limited Company</title><link>http://localhost/register/privatelimitedcompany/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/register/privatelimitedcompany/</guid><description>It is the most popular type of business entity in India. A Private Limited Company can be registered with minimum 2 members. Most of the startups prefer to be registered as a Private Limited Company as it has numerous advantages like limited liability, easy fund raising from outside etc.</description></item><item><title>Producer Company</title><link>http://localhost/register/producercompany/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/register/producercompany/</guid><description>A legally formed company with the aim to improve the standard of living of farmers and agriculturists can be defined as a “Producer Company”. Producer Company can be formed by 10 individuals (or more) or 2 institutions or more or by a combination of both (10 individuals and 2 institutions) having one of the following as their business objective:
Production Harvesting Procurement Grading Pooling Handling Marketing Export Selling Such a company can have only equity capital, require a minimum of five directors and an authorized capital of Rs.</description></item><item><title>Public Limited Company</title><link>http://localhost/register/publiclimitedcompany/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/register/publiclimitedcompany/</guid><description>The public Limited companies are suitable for large scale of business where the capital requirement is very high, and the company is willing to obtain money from the public at large. A Public Limited Company can be registered with minimum 7 members and with no maximum limit. There should be at least 3 directors, out of which one director must be a resident in India.</description></item><item><title>Section 8 Company</title><link>http://localhost/register/section8company/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/register/section8company/</guid><description>Section 8 company is suitable for the non-profit objectives such as the promotion of commerce, art, science, sports, education, research, social, welfare, religion, charity, protection of the environment and the like. The process of incorporation of a section 8 company is similar to that of any other company registration in India with an additional requirement of a license from the central government under section 8 of the companies act, 2013.</description></item><item><title>Sole Proprietorship</title><link>http://localhost/register/soleproprietorship/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://localhost/register/soleproprietorship/</guid><description>The simplest and most popular form of an unincorporated business that is owned and managed by a single owner. They are easy to establish and dismantle, due to a lack of government involvement. By acquiring local licenses, a sole proprietor can register his business easily. This type of business is ideal for those who are entering into the business for the first time. Many business begin as sole proprietorships and graduate to more complex form of business as it develops.</description></item></channel></rss>