<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Manage your compliances on Cosec Consultants</title><link>https://gopkumr.github.io/compliance/</link><description>Recent content in Manage your compliances on Cosec Consultants</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gopkumr.github.io/compliance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Event based compliances</title><link>https://gopkumr.github.io/compliance/eventbasedcompliances/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://gopkumr.github.io/compliance/eventbasedcompliances/</guid><description>Event based compliances are those which gets triggered upon the happening of certain events like change in directors, change of registered office, change in authorized share capital etc. Hence, it is necessary that the happening of such events get tracked and compliances met with on time in order to avoid penalties or additional fees.
Some of the event based compliances of companies are mentioned below:
Change in registered office Change in directors or KMP Increase in authorized share capital Filing of resolutions and agreements Increase in paid up share capital Change in secured borrowing Application for KYC of directors Declaration of commencement of business</description></item><item><title>Mandatory compliances</title><link>https://gopkumr.github.io/compliance/mandatorycompliances/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 12:29:40 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://gopkumr.github.io/compliance/mandatorycompliances/</guid><description>Every company should mandatorily follow various compliances from the incorporation stage. Managing the day to day operations of your business and compliance with the corporate laws, procedures and timelines can be a tedious work for any entrepreneur. To stay disciplined and to ensure fulfilment of compliances in the mentioned time frame without any interest or penalty, it is essential for the companies to take the help of professionals. Following are the mandatory compliances for a Private Limited Company: ##Filing of disclosure of interest by directors Appointment of first auditor and subsequent auditors Filing of annual financial statements and annual returns of companies Filing of statement of solvency and annual return of LLP’s Statutory audit of accounts</description></item></channel></rss>